Guide to the Jonathan Edwards Collection
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Writings of Jonathan Edwards, c. 1720-84; Series I; 10.3; (21 boxes)
  - SERMONS
    - REV. 14:18-19: "That God sometimes defers the punishment of sinners till they are fully ripe for destruction" (p. 3), n.d.
      See: Box 14, folder 1144
    - REV. 15:7: "Obs. 1. The principal subject spoken of in the text is the wrath of God. 2. How God is here described as he that liveth forever and ever" (p. 1), 1745/6 Mar (Box 12, Folder 915)
    - REV. 17:11: "[The] subject that I would now insist upon from these words is the fall of Antichrist" (p. 1), 1746 Jul 10 (Box 12, Folder 916)
      "Fast on occasion of the Expedition to Canada"
    - REV. 17:14: "I. Those that are Christ's and belonging to him, tis of God that they are so. II. They that belong to Jesus Christ, they are faithful to Christ" (p. 4) (Box 12, Folder 917)
    - REV. 18:20: "When the saints in glory shall see the wrath of God executed on ungodly men, it will be no occasion of grief to 'em, but of rejoicing" (p. 5), 1733 Mar (Box 12, Folder 918)
    - REV. 19:1: "The work and business of saints and angels in heaven consist very much in praising God" (p. 1), 1754 Nov 28
      See: Box 14, folder 1145
      Preached to Stockbridge Indians Nov. 28, 1754 Thanksgiving Day
    - REV. 19:2-3: "Tis not inconsistent with the attributes of God to punish ungodly men with a misery that is eternal" (p. 4), n.d. (Box 12, Folder 919)
    - REV. 19:5-6: "Christ leads the heavenly assembly in their praises" (p. 2), 1748, 1751 (Box 12, Folder 920)
    - REV. 19:11-12: "He that is to be the judge of men hath his eyes as a flame of fire" (p. 3), 1734, 1753 (Box 12, Folder 921)
    - REV. 19:13: "...that Christ is as it were clothed with a vesture dipped 1. in his own blood; 2. in the blood of his enemies" (p. 1), 1750-53 (Box 12, Folder 922)
      Preached to Stockbridge Indians; "preached at Newark," and "at Westborough"
    - REV. 19:15: "In hell is inflicted the fierceness of the wrath of a being that is almighty" (p. 4), 1734 Apr (Box 12, Folder 923)
    - REV. 20:6: "[First] insist on the negative part of their happiness, that the second death hath no power over them. "[Secondly] on the positive part of their happiness, viz. that of their being priests and kings" (p. 1), 1742 Aug (Box 12, Folder 924)
    - REV. 20:11: "When God shall appear at the day [of judgment] heaven and earth will flee away as though they could not bear his dreadful and wrathful presence" (p. 1), 1741, 1755 (Box 12, Folder 925)
    - REV. 21:2: "application. 2. To exhort all earnestly to seek to be made partakers of the great blessings and privileges of this glorious day" (p. 2), 1741/2 Feb (Box 12, Folder 926)
    - REV. 21:6: "There is a time coming when God's grand design in all his various works and dispensations from age to age will be completed and his end fully obtained" (p. 1), 1744 Dec (Box 12, Folder 927)
    - REV. 21:8: "I would shew how or in what is represented to us by the wicked's hereafter being cast into a lake of fire and brimstone. 2. How it is said that they shall have their part in it. 3. Why this is called the second death. 4. and lastly, I would warn all from hence to take heed..." (p. 3), 1744/5 Jan (Box 12, Folder 928-930)
    - REV. 21:18: "That there is nothing upon earth that will suffice to represent to us the glories of heaven" (p. 4), n.d.
      See: Box 14, folders 1146-1147
    - REV. 22:3: "That the happiness of the saints in heaven consists partly in that they there serve God" (p. 2), n.d. (Box 12, Folder 931)
    - REV. 22:3-5: "Text: And there shall be no more curse." "1. No more misery or sorrow... 2. God and Christ shall be there...", 1753 Nov
      See: Box 14, folder 1148
    - REV. 22:5: "The saints in heaven shall have light without any darkness" (p. 1), 1756 Aug
      See: Box 14, folder 1149
    - REV. 22:11-12: "The time will come that as men are at that time, whether good or bad, so they will be to all eternity; they will never change" (p. 1), 1753 Nov
      See: Box 14, folder 1150
    - REV. 22:12: "Christ will quickly come to judge men for what they do in the world" (p. 1), 1753 Nov
      See: Box 14, folder 1151
    - REV. 22:16-17: "Both the Bridegroom and the Bride do with united voice freely and earnestly invite poor sinners to the entertainments of the wedding of the Lamb" (p. 5), 1741, 1753 (Box 12, Folder 932)
    - REV. 22:17: "Nothing is required in order to have all the blessings of the gospel but willingly receiving" (p. 1), n.d. (Box 12, Folder 933)
    - Sermon notebook, marked in pencil "19," used subsequently as a ledger book by [William] Fonda
      See: Box 14, folder 1152
    - Sermon notebook, marked in pencil "14", [1736-38]
      See: Box 14, folder 1153
    - Last sermon notebook used at Date: Northampton, [ca. 1738-56]
      See: Box 14, folder 1154
      Includes text and doctrines of the "Farewell Sermon"
    - Outline of a lecture to the Stockbridge Indians
      See: Box 14, folder 1155
      For a special meeting called to consider the problem of the "Trade of getting too much to drink"
    - Oversize Sermons
      Folders 934-1155 contain oversize sermons, stored separately in boxes 13-14.
      - GEN. 1:27: "That God has given men...", 1751 Aug (Box 13, Folder 934)
      - GEN. 3:17-19: "the circumstances of...", [post 1756 Mar] (Box 13, Folder 935)
      - GEN. 32:24-32: "Jesus Christ...", 1754 May (Box 13, Folder 936)
      - EX. 34:6-7: "God is an infinitely...", 1753 Jan (Box 13, Folder 937)
      - DEUT. 30:19: "I. The benefit that...", 1755 May (Box 13, Folder 938)
      - DEUT. 32:29: "That such persons are...", n.d. (Box 13, Folder 939)
      - DEUT. 32:39: "Prop. I. There is but...", 1752 Jul (Box 13, Folder 940)
      - DEUT. 33:29: "They that have God to...", 1754 Dec (Box 13, Folder 941)
      - I SAM. 17:45-47: "For men to trust...", 1755 Jul[?] (Box 13, Folder 942)
      - II KI. 7:3-4: "That a possibility...", n.d. (Box 13, Folder 943)
      - II CHR. 20:6: "God is he that...", 1755 Mar 5 (Box 13, Folder 944)
      - JOB 1:21: "...we bring nothing of...", n.d. (Box 13, Folder 945)
      - JOB 7:7: "Subject, the mortality of...", 1751 (Box 13, Folder 946)
      - JOB 9:4: "God is infinitely strong", 1753 Jan (Box 13, Folder 947)
      - JOB 9:4-6: "I. All the strength and...", 1756 Jan (Box 13, Folder 948)
      - JOB 11:7-9: "God's strength is such...", 1751 Nov (Box 13, Folder 949)
      - JOB 14:5: "That God unalterably...", n.d. (Box 13, Folder 950)
      - JOB 20:12-14: "I. There are some...", 1754 May (Box 13, Folder 951)
      - JOB 28:28: "That wisdom does above...", n.d. (Box 13, Folder 952)
      - JOB 31:14: "They that are going on...", 1756 Apr (Box 13, Folder 953)
      - PS. 1:1: "First. Great difference...", 1755 Aug (Box 13, Folder 954)
      - PS. 1:3: "Christ is to the heart of...", [1751?] Aug (Box 13, Folder 955)
      - PS. 5:4-5: "Subject: the infinite...", 1752 Mar (Box 13, Folder 956)
      - PS. 14:1: "There certainly is a God", 1752 Dec (Box 13, Folder 957)
      - PS. 19:7-10: "The good that is...", n.d. (Box 13, Folder 958)
      - PS. 27:4: "Tis the heart of a truly...", 1752 Mar (Box 13, Folder 959)
      - PS. 27:4: "Tis our duty to love the...", 1756 Oct (Box 13, Folder 960)
      - PS. 37:16: "Riches of the wicked...", 1756 Apr (Box 13, Folder 961)
      - PS. 39:5: "The time men have to...", 1753 Mar (Box 13, Folder 962)
      - PS. 84:10: "A day spent in the...", 1752 May (Box 13, Folder 963)
      - PS. 89:6: "God is infinitely...", n.d. (Box 13, Folder 964-965)
      - PS. 95:7-8: "That it is our great...", n.d. (Box 13, Folder 966)
      - PS. 102:25-26: "That this present...", n.d. (Box 13, Folder 967-968)
      - PS. 112:1: "Good men are happy men", 1750/1 Feb (Box 13, Folder 969)
      - PS. 115:1: "That it is the temper...", n.d. (Box 13, Folder 970)
      - PS. 119:1-6: "I. He that is a good...", 1754 Mar (Box 13, Folder 971)
      - PS. 119:18: "Men are naturally...", [1751?] Oct (Box 13, Folder 972)
      - PS. 119:60: "That we ought to make...", n.d. (Box 13, Folder 973)
      - PS. 119:60: "Man is made to differ...", 1751 Sep (Box 13, Folder 974)
      - PS. 119:60-61: "Men ought to be...", 1754 Mar (Box 13, Folder 975)
      - PS. 145:15-21: "All creatures in...", 1753 Nov 1 (Box 13, Folder 976)
      - PS. 147:1: "Its a very decent and..." (Box 13, Folder 977)
      - PROV. 1:24-31: "Christ calls a...", 1755 Jun (Box 13, Folder 978)
      - PROV. 2:1-6: "1. Receive the words...", 1753 Oct (Box 13, Folder 979)
      - PROV. 8:10: "The grace of God in...", 1756 May (Box 13, Folder 980)
      - PROV. 8:31: "Christ delighted in...", 1752 Mar (Box 13, Folder 981)
      - PROV. 8:34-36: "1. What it is to...", 1752 Apr (Box 13, Folder 982)
      - PROV. 13:20: "If men will keep...", 1755 Jun (Box 13, Folder 983)
      - PROV. 18:10: "How Christ is a...", 1754 Sep (Box 13, Folder 984)
      - PROV. 19:8: "God in directing of us...", 1756 Jun (Box 13, Folder 985)
      - PROV. 24:13-14: "That it would be...", n.d. (Box 13, Folder 986)
      - PROV. 28:1: "Righteousness tends to...", 1754 Sep (Box 13, Folder 987)
      - PROV. 29:25: "They are safe that...", n.d. (Box 13, Folder 988)
      - ECCL. 8:8: "I. Most men are very...", 1755 Mar (Box 13, Folder 989)
      - ECCL. 8:11: "I. That God will...", 1753 May (Box 13, Folder 990)
      - ECCL. 9:10: "I. What [men] must do...", 1751 Dec (Box 13, Folder 991)
      - ECCL. 12:1: "By remembering [our...]", 1750/1 Feb (Box 13, Folder 992)
      - CANT. 1:3: "That Jesus Christ is...", 1733 Jun (Box 13, Folder 993)
      - IS. 3:10: "That a good man is a...", n.d. (Box 13, Folder 994)
      - IS. 6:3: "God is an infinitely holy...", 1753 Jan (Box 13, Folder 995)
      - IS. 35:8: "Those only that are holy...", n.d. (Box 13, Folder 996)
      - IS. 52:15: "The suffering of Christ...", 1752 Jul 26 (Box 13, Folder 997)
      - IS. 53:3: Text: "A man of sorrows...", 1753 Jul (Box 13, Folder 998)
      - IS. 53:7: "...suffered much from...", 1752 May (Box 13, Folder 999)
      - IS. 55:1-3: "Obs. I. All mankind...", 1755 May (Box 13, Folder 1000)
      - IS. 55:6: "How men should seek and...", 1755 Aug (Box 13, Folder 1001)
      - IS. 55:7-9: "The kindness of God is...", 1752 Nov 16 (Box 13, Folder 1002)
      - IS. 57:15: "I. God is the eternal...", 1754 Apr (Box 13, Folder 1003)
      - IS. 61:1: "Christ is come into the...", 1753 Oct (Box 13, Folder 1004)
      - JER. 50:6: "Christ is as [it] were...", 1755 Jun (Box 13, Folder 1005)
      - EZEK. 7:16: "That at a time when a...", n.d. (Box 13, Folder 1006-1007)
      - EZEK. 18:30-32: "I. God will judge...", 1754 Jun (Box 13, Folder 1008)
      - EZEK. 22:14: "I. When God comes to...", 1753 May (Box 13, Folder 1009)
      - EZEK. 33:7-9: "Tis kind and...", 1754 Nov (Box 13, Folder 1010)
      - HOS. 13:9: "Those sinners that are...", n.d. (Box 13, Folder 1011)
      - JOEL 2:12-13: "1. If men would...", 1753 Apr (Box 13, Folder 1012)
      - HAB. 1:13: "That [God] exceedingly...", 1752 May (Box 13, Folder 1013)
      - HAG. 1:5: "Tis the most important...", n.d. (Box 13, Folder 1014)
      - ZECH. 4:7: "The gospel dispensation...", n.d. (Box 13, Folder 1015)
      - MATT. 1:21: "...he shall save his...", 1755 Sep (Box 13, Folder 1016)
      - MATT. 3:7-12: "I. Sin makes men's...", 1753 Sep (Box 13, Folder 1017)
      - MATT. 5:3: "Those persons that are...", n.d. (Box 13, Folder 1018)
      - MATT. 5:3: "1. What is meant by...", 1752 Aug 2 (Box 13, Folder 1019)
      - MATT. 5:4: "I. What the mourning is...", 1752 Aug (Box 13, Folder 1020)
      - MATT. 5:8: "1. What it is to be...", 1752 Aug (Box 13, Folder 1021)
      - MATT. 6:19-20: "1. We should not be...", 1752 Apr (Box 13, Folder 1022)
      - MATT. 6:33: "By the kingdom of God...", 1751 Jul (Box 13, Folder 1023)
      - MATT. 7:13-14: "All mankind of all...", 1750/1 Jan (Box 13, Folder 1024)
      - MATT. 7:14: "Tis a hard thing to...", n.d. (Box 13, Folder 1025)
      - MATT. 7:24-27: "By the house which...", 1751 Jul (Box 13, Folder 1026)
      - MATT. 10:14-15: "They that will not...", 1755 Mar (Box 13, Folder 1027)
      - MATT. 10:37: "Doc. 1. If men don't...", 1752 Jul (Box 13, Folder 1028)
      - MATT. 11:28: "That Christ will...", n.d. (Box 13, Folder 1029)
      - MATT. 11:28: "1. What it is to come...", 1752 Aug (Box 13, Folder 1030)
      - MATT. 11:29-30: "I. How we should...", 1752 Aug (Box 13, Folder 1031)
      - MATT. 12:42: "It would be worth the...", 1754 Jul (Box 13, Folder 1032)
      - MATT. 13:8: "Doc. 1. There are some...", 1752 Mar (Box 13, Folder 1033)
      - MATT. 13:37-43: "I. Good men are...", 1754 May (Box 13, Folder 1034)
      - MATT. 13:40-43: "1. This world will...", 1752 Oct (Box 13, Folder 1035)
      - MATT. 13:42: "Subject: the misery...", 1753 Apr (Box 13, Folder 1036)
      - MATT. 13:47-50: "So none ought to...", 1750 Jan (Box 13, Folder 1037)
      - MATT. 16:26: "That the salvation of...", n.d. (Box 13, Folder 1038-1039)
      - MATT. 17:5: "I. Christ is the Son...", 1753 May (Box 13, Folder 1040)
      - MATT. 21:5: "The external meanness...", n.d. (Box 13, Folder 1041)
      - MATT. 22:1-14: "Obs. 1. The church...", 1755 Apr (Box 13, Folder 1042)
      - MATT. 22:37-38: "1. What it is to...", 1753 Apr (Box 13, Folder 1043)
      - MATT. 22:39: "That we should love...", 1753 Apr (Box 13, Folder 1044)
      - MATT. 23:37: [Christ] is ready to...", 1754 Jan (Box 13, Folder 1045)
      - MATT. 25:1-13: "Obs. 1. Christ is...", 1752 Dec (Box 13, Folder 1046)
      - MATT. 28:6-7: "1. How he rose...", 1754 Feb (Box 13, Folder 1047)
      - MATT. 28:19-20: "4. They that are...", [ca. 1751-57?] (Box 13, Folder 1048)
      - MARK 10:17-27: "Obs. 1. There are...", 1754 Feb (Box 13, Folder 1049)
      - MARK 16:15-16: "What is meant by ...", 1750/1, 1752 (Box 13, Folder 1050)
      - LUKE 1:77-79: "I. God's people have...", 1753 Dec (Box 13, Folder 1051)
      - LUKE 2:6-14: "I. What was that was...", 1753 Dec (Box 13, Folder 1052)
      - LUKE 2:10-11: "The word of God...", 1756 Apr (Box 13, Folder 1053)
      - LUKE 2:14: "That the Son of God by...", n.d. (Box 13, Folder 1054)
      - LUKE 2:14: "That Christ's appearing...", n.d. (Box 13, Folder 1055)
      - LUKE 4:18: "I. Shew you how the...", 1755 Jul (Box 13, Folder 1056)
      - LUKE 5:5-6: "That it is our best...", n.d. (Box 13, Folder 1057)
      - LUKE 6:45: "The speech of their...", 1753 Aug (Box 13, Folder 1058)
      - LUKE 6:45: "I. A wicked man has a...", 1753 Aug (Box 13, Folder 1059)
      - LUKE 8:26-39: "II. How wicked men...", 1754 Jun (Box 13, Folder 1060)
      - LUKE 9:23: "That if we would be...", n.d. (Box 13, Folder 1061)
      - LUKE 9:23: "I. Why it is necessary...", 1755 Aug (Box 13, Folder 1062)
      - LUKE 9:56: "Christ came into the...", 1754 Sep (Box 13, Folder 1063)
      - LUKE 11:24-26: "I. The devil...", 1755 Jul (Box 13, Folder 1064)
      - LUKE 11:27-28: "That the hearing...", 1751, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 1065)
      - LUKE 13:5: "Without true repentance...", n.d. (Box 14, Folder 1066)
      - LUKE 13:7: "A people that live...", 1751 Jun (Box 14, Folder 1067)
      - LUKE 14:16: "Obs. 1. The provision...", 1752 Nov (Box 14, Folder 1068)
      - LUKE 15:3-7: "Christ is to his...", 1752 Nov (Box 14, Folder 1069)
      - LUKE 15:11-24: "I. God is the...", 1753 Dec (Box 14, Folder 1070)
      - LUKE 16:19: "1. God is as willing...", 1753 Jun (Box 14, Folder 1071)
      - LUKE 16:22-23: "That which I intend...", 1751 Jul (Box 14, Folder 1072)
      - LUKE 16:27-28: "When [men] come...", 1756 May (Box 14, Folder 1073)
      - LUKE 18:1: "I. What is prayer...", 1753 May (Box 14, Folder 1074)
      - LUKE 18:13: "Now therefore you, if...", 1750/1, 1752 (Box 14, Folder 1075)
      - LUKE 19:10: "What is meant is that...", 1751 Jun (Box 14, Folder 1076)
      - LUKE 21:36: "I. Many dreadful...", [1758 Jan 15] (Box 14, Folder 1077)
      - LUKE 24:47: "In speaking from this...", 1751 Oct (Box 14, Folder 1078)
      - JOHN 1:12: "Good men whose hearts...", 1750/1, 1752 (Box 14, Folder 1079)
      - JOHN 1:12-13: "I. How true...", 1755 (Box 14, Folder 1080)
      - JOHN 1:29: "1. How that Christ is...", 1750 Feb (Box 14, Folder 1081)
      - JOHN 1:46: "Should come to Christ...", 1752 Dec (Box 14, Folder 1082)
      - JOHN 6:68: "It is by Christ alone...", n.d. (Box 14, Folder 1083)
      - JOHN 7:34: "Some men seek salvation...", 1752 Apr (Box 14, Folder 1084)
      - JOHN 8:12: "That Jesus Christ is...", n.d. (Box 14, Folder 1085)
      - JOHN 8:34: "That wicked men are...", n.d. (Box 14, Folder 1086)
      - JOHN 10:27: "Hear Christ's voice...", 1754 Jul (Box 14, Folder 1087)
      - JOHN 15:5: "That Christ Jesus is...", n.d. (Box 14, Folder 1088)
      - ACTS 2:37: "Commonly sinners before...", 1751 Nov (Box 14, Folder 1089)
      - ACTS 3:22-23: "I. Christ is a great...", 1756 Apr (Box 14, Folder 1090)
      - ACTS 11:12-13: "Now I am come to...", 1750/1 Jan (Box 14, Folder 1091)
      - ACTS 14:26-27: "Tis a special and...", 1753 May (Box 14, Folder 1092)
      - ACTS 16:9: "This may teach you how ...", 1751 Aug (Box 14, Folder 1093)
      - ACTS 16:29-31: "I. They that are...", 1753 Feb (Box 14, Folder 1094)
      - ACTS 16:30: "Tis of exceeding great...", 1755 Aug (Box 14, Folder 1095)
      - ROM. 1:21: "The subject. The great...", 1751 Nov 7 (Box 14, Folder 1096)
      - ROM. 1:24: "God sometimes punishes...", n.d. (Box 14, Folder 1097)
      - ROM. 8:34: "Tis impossible that...", 1755 Sep (Box 14, Folder 1098)
      - ROM. 12:1: "Tis our most reasonable...", n.d. (Box 14, Folder 1099)
      - ROM. 12:12: "I. Tis all men's duty...", 1755 Jun (Box 14, Folder 1100)
      - ROM. 12:18: "It is an indispensable..." (Box 14, Folder 1101)
      - I COR. 6:19-20: "1. How Christians...", 1753 Apr (Box 14, Folder 1102)
      - I COR. 6:19-20: "I. Christians are...", 1754 Feb (Box 14, Folder 1103)
      - I COR. 10:17: "The Lord's Supper...", 1750/1 Jan (Box 14, Folder 1104)
      - I COR. 11:23-25: "I. What is meant...", 1752 Jan (Box 14, Folder 1105)
      - I COR. 11:27: "Here, 1. I will tell...", 1750/1 Jan (Box 14, Folder 1106)
      - I COR. 11:28: "[Text: But leave a...", 1751 Dec (Box 14, Folder 1107)
      - II COR. 4:3-4: "I. How the gospel...", 1754 Dec (Box 14, Folder 1108)
      - II COR. 4:7: "That God is pleased...", n.d. (Box 14, Folder 1109)
      - II COR. 4:18: "But there is another...", 1751 Aug (Box 14, Folder 1110)
      - II COR. 5:17: "1. What is meant by...", 1751 Sep (Box 14, Folder 1111)
      - EPH. 4:22-24: "I. Men naturally are...", 1752 Jun (Box 14, Folder 1112)
      - PHIL. 1:21: "Everyone that is a...", n.d. (Box 14, Folder 1113)
      - PHIL. 1:21: "Death is gainful to...", n.d. (Box 14, Folder 1114)
      - PHIL. 2:7: "[The incarnation and...", 1756 Aug (Box 14, Folder 1115)
      - PHIL. 2:8: "Our Lord Jesus Christ...", 1756 (Box 14, Folder 1116)
      - COL. 1:12: "If men would go to...", 1756 Aug (Box 14, Folder 1117)
      - I THESS. 5:5: "Shew how true...", 1751 Dec (Box 14, Folder 1118)
      - II THESS. 2:13: "He whose work it...", 1753 Feb (Box 14, Folder 1119)
      - II THESS. 3:10-13: "...the sin of...", 1752 Jul (Box 14, Folder 1120)
      - I TIM. 3:16: "Jesus Christ is both...", 1753 Feb (Box 14, Folder 1121)
      - TITUS 1:2: "God hath made provision...", 1751 Dec (Box 14, Folder 1122)
      - HEB. 3:7-11: "They that live under..." (Box 14, Folder 1123)
      - HEB. 9:12: "Jesus Christ is both...", n.d. (Box 14, Folder 1124)
      - HEB. 9:27: "All men must certainly...", n.d. (Box 14, Folder 1125-1126)
      - HEB. 9:27: "All men of all nations...", 1750, 1752 (Box 14, Folder 1127)
      - HEB. 11:16: "I. This world is an...", 1754 Jan (Box 14, Folder 1128)
      - HEB. 13:7-8: ["Farewell sermon...", [17]58 Jan (Box 14, Folder 1129)
      - JAMES 1:12 "The doctrine was, that...", n.d. (Box 14, Folder 1130)
      - JAMES 1:25: "In God's service is...", n.d. (Box 14, Folder 1131)
      - I PET. 1:8: "Three things: loving...", 1753 Oct (Box 14, Folder 1132)
      - I PET. 1:15: "That Christians are...", n.d. (Box 14, Folder 1133-1134)
      - I PET. 4:7: "It becomes [us] to be...", 1752 Jan 1 (Box 14, Folder 1135)
      - II PET. 2:4: "The fall of the...", 1753 Feb (Box 14, Folder 1136)
      - I JOHN 3:10: "All mankind through...", 1756 Mar (Box 14, Folder 1137)
      - I JOHN 5:3: "The true love to God...", n.d. (Box 14, Folder 1138)
      - JUDE 13: "The misery of the wicked...", 1756 Jul (Box 14, Folder 1139)
      - REV. 1:7: "...this coming of Christ...", 1750/1, 1752 (Box 14, Folder 1140)
      - REV. 3:20: "The Lord Jesus Christ...", 1750/1 Feb (Box 14, Folder 1141)
      - REV. 6:13-17: "I. Tho' now many...", 1754 Jul (Box 14, Folder 1142)
      - REV. 14:4: "The saints are those...", 1756 Feb (Box 14, Folder 1143)
      - REV. 14:18-19: "That God sometimes...", n.d. (Box 14, Folder 1144)
      - REV. 19:1: "The work and business...", 1754 Nov 28 (Box 14, Folder 1145)
      - REV. 21:18: "That there is nothing...", n.d. (Box 14, Folder 1146-1147)
      - REV. 22:3-5: Text: "And there shall...", 1753 Nov (Box 14, Folder 1148)
      - REV. 22:5: "The saints in heaven...", 1756 Aug (Box 14, Folder 1149)
      - REV. 22:11-12: "The time will come...", 1753 Nov (Box 14, Folder 1150)
      - REV. 22:12: "Christ will quickly...", 1753 Nov (Box 14, Folder 1151)
      - Sermon notebook, marked in pencil "19", n.d. (Box 14, Folder 1152)
      - Sermon notebook, marked in pencil "14", [1736-38] (Box 14, Folder 1153)
      - Last sermon notebook used at Northampton, [ca. 1738-56] (Box 14, Folder 1154)
      - Outline of a lecture to the Stockbridge Indians (Box 14, Folder 1155)
      - Fragment, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 1156)
        On verso, part of bill of sale or receipt for purchase by Edwards of "a Negro girle named Venus"
      - Fragment, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 1157)
        On verso, fragment concerning testimony of "Bathsheba Negro"
      - Fragment, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 1158)
        On verso, note by Sarah Edwards, dated 1744 Mar 26
      - Fragment, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 1159)
        On verso, note from Chester Williams
      - Fragment, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 1160)
        On verso, letter from Chester Williams, dated 1741/2 Feb 15
      - Fragment, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 1161)
        On verso, letter (signature missing) requesting that Edwards preach an ordination sermon
      - Fragments, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 1162-1196)
      - Fragment, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 1197)
        On verso, letter from Hulda Hopkins
      - Fragment, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 1198)
        On verso, letter from Sarah Noyes to Sarah Edwards, dated 1742 Oct 31
      - Fragment, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 1199)
        On verso, letter from [Gideon Hawley?] to Jonathan Edwards, 1756 Dec 28
  - NOTEBOOKS AND MEMORANDA
    - "Answer to Mr. Williams"
      Reply to Solomon Williams on "the qualifications necessary to lawful communion"
      - First half of draft, marked on cover "Printed. Book 3,", n.d. (Box 15, Folder 1200)
      - Second half of draft, marked on cover "Printed. Book 4" (Box 15, Folder 1201)
    - "Catalogue", notebook, manuscript list of books Edwards read or intended to read, ca. 1722-58 (Box 15, Folder 1202)
      A loose leaf inserted between the front cover and first page is a list started before the Catalogue
    - "Controversies", marked on front cover "Controversy Book C" and "Sundries" (Box 15, Folder 1203)
    - Defense of the authenticity of the Pentateuch as a work of Moses and the historicity of the Old Testament narratives, notebook made from pages of Arnauld's De la fréquente communion (Box 15, Folder 1204)
      With leaves 126/7 and 130/1 which had been separated from the notebook. "Continuation of 'Notes on Scripture' no. 416."